MOHAMED DIOP

A resourceful and reliable software engineer with 4 years of experience developing intuitive multi-platform software solutions and a background in business. I am a firm believer that with a sound mind and patience, every problem has a solution and value a peaceful and inspiring work environment above all.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Software Engineering Immersive

General Assembly | Los Angeles, California | September 2021 - December 2021

- · Completed 720+ hours of full stack software development
- Developed real world responsive applications using NodeJS, ExpressJS, React,
 Django and much more
- · Built and maintained repositories consistently on Github
- Took Computer Science courses
- Pitched 4 projects including one made in teams using the Mob programming technique
- Gained access to a network of 19,430+ alumni

ERP Implementation Consultant

One Age Group | Dakar, Senegal | March 2020 - August 2021

- Supported development, security and sale of professional ERP and CRM solutions using Odoo (Open Source ERP and CRM)
- Led stakeholder presentations, building case for product implementation and showcasing solutions in real-world scenarios
- Met goals set by clients, garnering widespread support and growing customer base

Full Stack Mobile App Developer

Planet Kebab | Dakar, Senegal | January 2020 - March 2020

- Collected and defined customer requirements
- Completed design projects to meet budget, equipment, performance and legal requirements
- Worked with clients to analyze computing and network needs and installed appropriate cloud infrastructures
- Led API and mobile app development using ExpressJS, MongoDB and React Native to meet requirements.

Full-Stack Software Engineer

Internway | Dakar, Senegal | January 2019 - December 2019

- Led database, web application and API development projects using the MERN stack
- · Wrote, filed and delivered technical documents
- Troubleshot software, web service and application problems
- Worked extensively with marketing and administrative teams to better understand market data in order to launch an intuitive solution for Internship seekers

CONTACT

3 310-890-7695

☑ mohamed.onbird@gmail.com

O Los Angeles, CA 90005

SKILLS

- Software Development Life Cycle
- Agile
- · Project Management
- Javascript
- Typescript
- NodeJS
- React
- React Native
- Python
- Django
- Ruby
- C#
- ASP.NET
- Java
- Rust
- SQL
- MongoDB
- · Git/Github
- Solidity
- Docker
- AWS
- Microsoft Azure

EDUCATION

Master of Science

Computer Science Sup'Info, Dakar Expected in August 2022

BBA

Business Administration BEM/Kedge Business School, Dakar/Bordeaux May 2018

LANGUAGES

Data Analyst

Wild Code School | Paris, France | September 2018 - December 2018

- · Completed 810 hours of general coding and Data Analysis
- Cleaned, aggregated and analyzed data to predict future outcomes or create data visualizations
- Completed real world descriptive and inferential analysis using Python and multiple data manipulation libraries such as Pandas, NumPy, SciPy, Scikit-learn, Tensorflow
- Studied and implemented the Netflix recommendation algorithm (Deep Learning)
- · Gained access to a network of 4000+ alumni

Full Stack Software Engineer

Le Wagon | Lyon, France | January 2018 - March 2018

- · Completed 660 hours of code
- Learned the Ruby on Rails framework for API and Web Application development
- Completed the Software Development Lifecycle for a variety of real world projects
- Gained skills in Agile development, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Git, Testing, Security, Software Architecture and Data Structures, SQL, MongoDB, Cloud Computing and much more
- · Pitched a variety of real world projects
- Gained access to a network of 12,940+ alumni all over the world



ACCOMPLISHMENTS

 Recipient of a Microsoft Accelerate Grant